joining me now with the latest is NBC News
现在与我连线的是NBC新闻的
business and data correspondent
商业与数据记者
Brian Chung so Brian
布莱恩·钟。那么布莱恩，
the markets
股市
don't seem to totally be sold on Trump's posts
似乎并不完全认可特朗普的发文
becoming a reality take us inside the numbers
会成真。带我们深入看看数据
what happened out there
今天市场发生了什么？
are they taking him seriously or literally or at all
他们是在认真对待、照字面理解，还是完全无视？
yeah well look
嗯，是这样的
when you talk about the closing numbers
谈到收盘数据
you can see them on the board ahead of you
你可以在前面的屏幕上看到
the Dow Jones down six tens of percent
道琼斯指数下跌0.6%
the s and P 500
标普500
the more broad base index down seven tens of percent
这个覆盖范围更广的指数下跌0.7%
and those tech heavy stocks were
而科技权重股
that would certainly include a heavier
其中当然包括权重更高的
waiting on companies like apple
像苹果这样的公司
down a little bit more by 1%
跌幅稍大，达到1%
but this isn't necessarily a
但这算不上是
you know Black Monday type of day
像"黑色星期一"那种暴跌
it's just simply a day where stocks ended
只是股市最终
marginally red so
小幅收跌的一天
I don't think that it's the markets
我不认为这是市场
necessarily freaking out
在恐慌性反应
over what's going on with these announcements
对这些声明的反应
but I do think broadly speaking
但我认为总体而言
there was this concern that uh
存在一种担忧...
you know look
你知道的
we had gotten over most of the crazy tear of headlines
我们刚熬过密集的新闻轰炸期
about a month ago and after the 90 day pause
大约一个月前，经过90天暂停期
and especially the escalation
特别是随着局势升级
especially with China uh
尤其是与中国的关系
there was maybe some thought within Wall Street
华尔街可能有人认为
that maybe this is going to be a quieter summer
今年夏天会比较平静
and then here
结果现在
you have the Friday before Memorial Day weekend
阵亡将士纪念日前的周五
the president
总统
kicking back up some of these tariff headlines
又重提关税议题
I do think that has the volatility
我认为这确实会导致
perhaps coming back marginally
波动性小幅回升
to Wall Street but again
但问题还是在于
the question here is what he's saying on true social
他在Truth Social上的发言
be to be taken literally or figuratively
该按字面理解还是象征性解读
that is kind of
这其实是
the ongoing story with this administration
这届政府的一贯作风
and that's something that Wall Streets
这也是华尔街
gonna have to grap with
必须应对的
as we continue to see these tariff threats
随着关税威胁持续
going forward right
对吧
and then another confusing call by the president uh
总统另一个令人困惑的呼吁
he's called on apple to make iPhones in the US
他要求苹果在美国生产iPhone
or face it tariff
否则将面临关税
is what he's calling for actually realistic
这个要求现实吗？
what exactly is he threatening here
他具体在威胁什么？
well originally in the morning
今天早上他最初
when he posted on Truth Social
在Truth Social发文时
suggesting that he was not only looking at
暗示不仅要针对
specifically Terrafing Apple
苹果公司加征关税
but terrafing a specific product line
还要针对特定产品线
the iPhone
iPhone
there were a lot of questions swirling around over
引发了许多疑问
how could the president do that
总统如何能做到？
yes they could use the emergency authorities
是的，可以动用紧急权力
and claim under national security interest
以国家安全为由
that you need to tear off an entire industry
对整个行业加税
but to take one specific company
但针对特定公司
then one specific product remained legally ambiguous
再指定某个产品，法律上仍存疑
although
不过
we did hear from the president in the Oval Office
我们确实听到总统在椭圆形办公室
just a few minutes ago where he did clarify that he
几分钟前澄清说，他
quote he didn't want to be unfair to apple
"不想对苹果不公平"
even though apple in the iPhone
尽管苹果和iPhone
were very clearly
显然就是
the specific target of his true social
他在Truth Social的明确目标
but he said that he would
但他说会
expand the scope of this particular tariff
扩大这项关税的范围
to cover essentially
涵盖所有
all smartphones that are coming into the United States
进入美国的智能手机
which would include and he name check the company
包括他点名的公司
Samsung a Korean phone that makes a lot of
三星，这家韩国手机制造商
a Korean phone maker that makes a lot of popular
生产多款流行的
Android based products so
安卓设备的公司
it does sound like
看来如果
if he does wanna follow through on this 25% tariff
真要实施这25%关税
it wouldn't just cover the iPhone Ryan
就不只是iPhone了，瑞恩
it would cover
会涵盖
all the smartphones that come into this country
所有进入美国的智能手机
which they're very few of them made entirely
而这些手机几乎都不是
basically here in the United States
完全在美国生产的
yeah of course the
当然，关键问题是
the key there will he follow through
他是否会落实
because he's threatened a lot of terrorists
因为他曾多次威胁加税
and not necessarily
但实际落实的
many of them actually manifest themselves
并不多
uh what else did we hear though
我们还听到
the president say about terrorists today
总统今天还说了什么？
it seemed to say
他似乎表示
indicate that these companies love to eat the tariffs
这些公司乐于承担关税
yeah well look
是的
there was the conversation of whether or not the
关于总统是否真的
you know president was actually
坚持要求
adamant on
这些公司承担成本
whether or not these companies should take these costs
存在讨论
there was a conversation that was reported that he had
据报道他曾与
had with Walmart suggesting that they should take uh
沃尔玛沟通，建议他们自行
the price increases themselves
消化涨价
as we know when it comes to the tariffs
我们都知道，关税
any importing company
任何进口公司
which in many cases are the American companies
很多情况下是美国公司
they're the ones that would have to pay for it
才是需要支付关税的
take a listen to this exchange
听听这段对话
with regards to his clarification
关于他的澄清
over where he thinks the tariffs should be paid for
关于他认为关税该由谁承担
sometimes the country will eat it
有时国家会承担
sometimes Walmart will eat it
有时沃尔玛会承担
and sometimes there'll be something to pay
有时需要额外支付
something extra I don't like it when a department suit
我不喜欢百货公司这样做
cause they'll do a lot of business
因为他们生意做得很大
but you know
但你知道
they announced record profits and everything else
他们公布了创纪录的利润
have to take out some of their profits
应该从利润里拿点钱出来
so make a little bit less money
少赚一点
but I don't want I don't want the consumer
但我不希望消费者
I don't want the consumer to pay
不希望消费者买单
but again
但话说回来